Okay, what's up y'all? We are back with
a brand new video. Make sure you like
and subscribe if you appreciate the
content. Today we are looking at the
brand new Min Max H3 in comfy UI. Let's
get started.
>> Okay, thank you to my associate. Really
appreciate it. Um, yeah, so like she
said, we're going over Min Max H3. Uh,
today we're only going to be going over
the reference model. There's two models
that came out, the text video / image to
video one and the reference one. I think
the reference one is the most
interesting.
The other one is basically what we've
been having. It's significantly better,
but it's basically, uh,
you know, normal
text to image, text to video and image
to video. Um, but the reference one is
different because we can use references,
right? Um, so here for this video I
generated as the intro, I used two
references. I used, uh, this character
sheet here. And I used, uh, this voice
here for the voice of the character. Uh,
if I play the voice real quick.
>> You made a promise. Maybe it's broken.
Okay.
>> So you get the point of the voice and
then this is the voice that was used in
the video.
>> Oh, we are back with a brand new video.
Make sure you like and subscribe if
>> Okay, so you can see that it used both
of the references to generate the video.
And, um, I would say the most important
part of,
getting good results with this model is
the prompting. Um, you will need to use
a LLM to get proper prompts for this
model. Uh, you're not writing prompts
manually for this, okay? Uh, you're
going to be
you're going to be wasting more time,
uh, writing the prompts than actually
generating your, uh, video. So,
um, honestly you should be using a LLM
whether it's locally or through some,
uh, uh
paid service or whatever. Uh, what do
you want to use? Grok, uh Gemini,
ChatGPT, Claude, whatever. Um just make
sure you give it the prompting guide.
I'll put the links to everything
obviously in the school post. Um and
yeah, okay? So,
prompting [music] really important. Uh
but once you got the prompting unlock,
the the rest of the model is super easy
to use. Just put in your references. Uh
and for your prompting, you you
>> [music]
>> uh basically um
specify your references, and then it's
going to build a prompt around those.
And uh yeah, so
here um
quick example. Uh you need uh your
reference images. You can add reference
videos. So, if you want to do character
replacement or um
motion control to some extent, you can
do it using a reference video.
Um the the the main problem I've seen
with uh the character replacement/motion
control using a reference
is that it's basically
pretty random, okay? It's not really
consistent if you're using a character.
Uh but if you're asking uh for a
replacement with something the model
already knows, so if I were to ask, uh
do a character replacement uh of the of
this guy uh to Deadpool, for example, it
would do it pretty much
uh
uh seamlessly. But if I were to ask to
replace um
this guy with my character here, I would
get
bad results like uh 75% of the time from
what I've tested. So,
I don't know if it's my approach that's
not the best or whatever, but um I'm
still figuring this out. So, I'll make a
an update on this
uh when I figure it out. I'm sure it's
doable um consistently, but uh just not
right now. So, that's pretty much uh the
references. You can add a voice or you
can just don't use a voice. You don't
need to.
Um but, you're going to get the voice
that it gives um to pretty much most
characters.
And then, I made a node here uh
megapixel resize. That's going to let
you basically choose the megapixel you
want to generate at. Um and if you use a
reference, you can use um you can plug
in an image to resize the image to the
megapixel you're going to generate at.
So,
uh I just made the node cuz I thought
the the original uh workflow was a
little bit convoluted uh without that.
And I think it's pretty useful. It would
be useful in other uh types of uh
generation as well.
Uh so, yeah. That's pretty much the
workflow. Nothing too crazy. Here, we go
over um the settings. So,
um
basic scheduler, we do eight steps. Uh I
didn't talk about that. Um
So, here, um we choose the ref model,
right? Uh we I use CG tension. It speeds
up the generation by probably like 50%
actually. So,
if you have it installed, uh use it
absolutely. Um
And then, here, you can kind of add your
uh turbo Laura's. So, if you don't want
to do the full amount of steps, so if
you don't want to do 25 steps, which is
going to be pretty slow on most PCs, uh
you can use a eight-step Laura. You can
use a four-step Laura if you prefer it
that.
Um but, yeah. So, those are your two
options. I'll put the links to
everything in the school post. And then,
uh for the shift, uh I would leave it as
is, but you can play around with the
values if uh you're getting bad results
on
uh the audio. Um and yeah.
If you do the full amount of steps, you
can use spectrum, which is going to
basically do an approximation of
the generation instead of being it being
deterministic.
So, it's basically going to predict what
happens, but that's going to give you
worse motion, obviously, because it's
not going to the full amount of steps.
It's basically skipping
every other step to
give you your result faster.
Okay?
So, that's pretty much it.
What else do I need to say? So,
the workflow uses VRAM debug nodes.
This is because
the text encoder is so [__] big that
if you try to load the text encoder and
then try to load the actual model,
you're going to run out of VRAM
immediately, and that's going to
basically slow down your sampling by a
lot. So, I added nodes that basically
after
the text encoder runs, it basically
wipes out the memory, and then you can
go into loading the actual model, and
after the model is done, it basically
resets it to zero again.
I say resets it, but basically sends the
model to your
normal RAM instead of actually keeping
it in your VRAM and causing slowdowns
and stuff like that.
That's the logic.
And then we have a preview override.
That's going to show you
>> [music]
>> the actual video while it's being
generated. So, if you see the results
are not what you're looking for
on the physics part, you can just cancel
it and run it again with a new seed.
Okay? So, that's basically it.
I'll do
what should I do actually? I can do
another prompt using my character sheet
here
and I'll do without the voice this time
just so we can see the original voice of
the model.
And yeah, so I'll I'll get a new prompt
and be right back. Let's get it.
Okay, so I got my prompt here. I'll just
run it and let's see. So
I added a new reference here. So that's
going to be a second character that's
going to be interacting with the first
one
and
it's basically going to be a street
interview type of
content.
As you can see it's pretty fast right
where we have the first images and we
can see
what it's basically going to look like.
If we go and see the speed
So obviously it's running on 590.
Most people are not going to get that
speed but
basically 11 seconds per iteration and
we doing eight here. We don't so we
doing eight steps. That's basically
going to be a minute and a half for a 10
second video which is not that bad.
Um
Obviously if you turn up the resolution
is going to
be
slower but
you're going to get [music]
higher quality results.
The the model is basically capped at
768p,
okay?
You could do more but it's not really
what it's trained for
and they said they're going to release
the upscaler which is going to let you
do 2K videos
right out the box. So
I'm waiting for that. Obviously I'm
going to cover it
but yeah, that's pretty much it. The
video is almost done.
Um, added this part here, RTX video
super resolution upscale. So, it's
basically doubling the resolution of the
uh first video. Um, and uh results are
not that bad, actually. Um, so let's
see.
And this is the final result.
>> Okay, so why did you get banned on every
platform? I don't really know, bro, but
they got me [__] up. She knows she's
not helping her case and does not care.
>> I don't know what she why she's saying
all that. Like, I didn't read the
prompt, but
whatever, you get the point. Um,
we have the two characters uh from the
reference.
And
uh
we got the video of those two
interacting. So, that's pretty much uh
it. I mean, there's a lot more you can
do. I'm not going to be going over
everything you can do in this video, uh
but that's uh that's that's why it's a
good model. You can do a lot with not
that much. You really only need two
things.
Uh you don't need all the masking and
all the Sam free and uh the the control
nets and all that [__] You could use
those, by the way. You could use control
nets um inputs and it should work, but
you don't really need that. So, yeah,
I'm going to stop here. Uh this was
pretty much just a quick overview of the
actual model.
Um,
if you guys want to see anything
specific, so uh you know, video
reference and stuff like that or uh
Laura training. I trained a Laura uh for
this model already. It works pretty well
uh with videos. Um, I didn't really test
with images, but I'm sure it could work
as well
uh with AI toolkit. Um, so yeah, if you
want to learn anything specific, let me
know. And uh next video is going to be
about the text to video and image to
video models. And uh yeah, that's pretty
much it. Shout out to everybody on
school. Make sure you subscribe and I'll
see you in the next one. Peace.